{"Topic": "MPs and MLAs", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Next to Uttar Pradesh, which of the following States has the highest number of seats in the Lok Sabha?", "op1": "Bihar", "op2": "Maharashtra", "op3": "West Bengal", "op4": "Andhra Pradesh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "How many members are nominated by the President of India to the Lok Sabha?", "op1": "12", "op2": "4", "op3": "2", "op4": "8", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which schedule to the Constitution of India details the allocation of seats in the Rajya Sabha per State/Union Territory?", "op1": "Seventh", "op2": "Second", "op3": "Fifth", "op4": "Fourth", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "As per the Constitution of India, the maximum permissible strength of the House of the People or the Lok Sabha is", "op1": "552", "op2": "545", "op3": "530", "op4": "540", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following States does not have a Legislative Council?", "op1": "Andhra Pradesh", "op2": "Maharashtra", "op3": "Bihar", "op4": "Tamilnadu", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many union Territories have a representation in the Rajya Sabha?", "op1": "Only 1", "op2": "Only 2", "op3": "Only 4", "op4": "All the 7", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following States has more than 1 Member of Parliament in the Lok Sabha?", "op1": "Meghalaya", "op2": "Nagaland", "op3": "Sikkim", "op4": "Mizoram", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following \u2018State \u2013 Number of lok Sabha MPs\u2019, combination is incorrect?", "op1": "Bihar - 40", "op2": "Tamilnadu - 37", "op3": "West Bengal - 42", "op4": "Maharshtra - 48", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the maximum permissible strength of the Legislative Assembly of a State?", "op1": "475", "op2": "525", "op3": "500", "op4": "545", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many States in India are bi-cameral in their governance structure?", "op1": "5", "op2": "6", "op3": "7", "op4": "4"}, {"Question": "As per the Constitution of India the Legislative Assembly should not consist of less than 60 members, but in practice which of the following states have less than 60 members?", "op1": "1, 2 and 3 only", "op2": "2, 3 and 4 only", "op3": "1, 3 and 4 only", "op4": "All the four", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Sikkim  2. Mizoram   3. Goa    4. Manipur", "op1": "15", "op2": "20", "op3": "22", "op4": "30", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "As per the Constitution, the maximum permissible number of MPs who may represent the Union Territories in the Lok Sabha is -", "op1": "1/4", "op2": "1/2", "op3": "1/3", "op4": "1/5", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "As per the Constitution, the strength of the Legislative Council is not to exceed _____ of the strength of the Legislative Assembly.", "op1": "60", "op2": "40", "op3": "50", "op4": "30", "Answer": 2}]}